<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-27T14:19:48+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/</id><title type="html">Happen Digital</title><subtitle>Content to make complicated things clear
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Stories, snories: right and wrong ways to use storytelling in marketing</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/11/06/stories-snories-right-and-wrong-ways-to-use-storytelling-in-marketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stories, snories: right and wrong ways to use storytelling in marketing" /><published>2017-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/11/06/stories-snories-right-and-wrong-ways-to-use-storytelling-in-marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/11/06/stories-snories-right-and-wrong-ways-to-use-storytelling-in-marketing.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s important to have believable or humorous stories as part of a mix of content in your marketing, with facts alongside creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdWeek recently published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adweek.com/agencies/advertising-isnt-storytelling/?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_feed%3BRZEy5oiCTH29rzSvoCYixw%3D%3D&quot;&gt;provocative comment piece&lt;/a&gt; about storytelling in advertising. Copywriter Marc Schwerin argues that the concept isn’t particularly helpful as most brands don’t actually have a story to tell and advertising formats aren’t conducive to storytelling because of their brevity. He believes advertising is most effective when it is interactive. By this he means playful: allowing the audience to solve a puzzle and enjoy the satisfaction of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I share some of Schwerin’s distrust of the term, which can be used to dress things up as more than they are. But I wouldn’t dismiss the use of storytelling in marketing as a whole. There’s plenty of evidence that humans respond to and seek out stories: anyone who is a parent will know that without the need to delve into neuroscience. It can also be helpful for organisations to have a story to explain ‘why’ they exist as long as it isn’t blatantly fictitious or risible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is important is to have believable or humorous stories as part of a mix of content in your marketing, with facts alongside creative. Happen doesn’t do the sort of traditional television and print advertising Schwerin is writing about. We work mostly online, providing editorial consultancy and training as well as creating content. But we do make content designed to raise awareness about our clients – what most people call adverts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes these tell a story, other times they don’t. One that did was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/teachfirst/videos/10155729430669577/&quot;&gt;short film we made recently for the charity Teach First&lt;/a&gt; about how a teacher inspired a troubled teenager to win a place at Oxford. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ZooplaUK/videos/10155244749313935/&quot;&gt;short Facebook animation we made for Zoopla&lt;/a&gt; didn’t, unless you consider ‘man buys dream home but gets stressed out because it’s up a mountain’ a cracking narrative. What matters is choosing the right approach for the client and what they’re trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing needs to give consumers the facts as well as stories, particularly in B2B marketing, where people spend longer researching their purchasing. Thinking about the whole customer journey is key: explain your goods and services when people are examining their options and provide reassurance when they’re on the brink of buying. In an era of ‘fake news’ people want to feel that they’re getting the information they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t preclude storytelling. Case studies are an effective way to reassure potential customers, and they’re usually better if they tell a story. Rather than merely explaining how the person or company uses your good or service, it is more engaging to explain what motivated them to buy it in the first place and what it has helped them to overcome and achieve. There might even be some emotion there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s important to have believable or humorous stories as part of a mix of content in your marketing, with facts alongside creative.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/11/06/Teach%20First%20illustration%201.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why you should explain the hows and whys of your charity work</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/09/17/why-you-should-explain-the-hows-and-whys-of-your-charity-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why you should explain the hows and whys of your charity work" /><published>2017-09-17T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-17T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/09/17/why-you-should-explain-the-hows-and-whys-of-your-charity-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/09/17/why-you-should-explain-the-hows-and-whys-of-your-charity-work.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of brands do charity work but few explain why they choose a particular cause or how they decided upon the best way to make a contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happen regularly does pro bono work, helping charities with content production, editorial training and their content strategy. We do this for altruistic reasons of course – we believe our skills make a real difference to the charities – but also because it stretches us and teaches us new things. We get something out of it too. It is core to our purpose as a content agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not unique in this. Charity work reveals a lot about a company’s expertise and values. This means it’s something worth explaining to your customers, as is what you as a company gain from the work. Does it sharpen your skills, motivate your staff or further a cause you believe in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/233725821&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently made a short pro bono film for the City of London Sinfonia about how it is different from other orchestras. The CLS wanted to explain how their outreach work is a part of their approach to music, not just an add-on. As well as classical concerts and collaborations with other artists, CLS members regularly perform in retirement homes and children’s hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussing this with Matthew Swann, chief executive of the CLS,  we had a light-bulb moment when he explained his belief that this work made the orchestra’s players better musicians. They have to improvise performing for children - something classical musicians don’t normally do – and this made them better, more responsive classical performers. As CLS principal clarinet Katherine Spencer puts it in the film: “I really don’t think you can do the evening work without the day work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hows and whys of a company’s charity work are ripe for elucidation. You should be explaining why you’re backing a particular cause and how your expertise is making difference, but also what you as an organisation are gaining from it too. That may not be immediately obvious, but it is worth thinking about how it fits into your communications and marketing strategy.
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;twttr.conversion.trackPid('ny50t', { tw_sale_amount: 0, tw_order_quantity: 0 });&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;
&amp;lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://analytics.twitter.com/i/adsct?txn_id=ny50t&amp;amp;amp;p_id=Twitter&amp;amp;amp;tw_sale_amount=0&amp;amp;amp;tw_order_quantity=0&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//t.co/i/adsct?txn_id=ny50t&amp;amp;amp;p_id=Twitter&amp;amp;amp;tw_sale_amount=0&amp;amp;amp;tw_order_quantity=0&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A lot of brands do charity work but few explain why they choose a particular cause or how they decided upon the best way to make a contribution.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/09/17/CLS-pic.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How best to use your team on camera</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/08/03/how-best-to-use-your-team-on-camera.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How best to use your team on camera" /><published>2017-08-03T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-03T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/08/03/how-best-to-use-your-team-on-camera</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/08/03/how-best-to-use-your-team-on-camera.html">&lt;p&gt;Considering casting your team in a marketing video? Here is how to get the best out of your staff in front of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve made quite a few films recently featuring our clients. It can be very effective but also challenging and it might not be right for every video. Here then is what you should keep in mind when considering putting your staff in front of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are good reasons to use professional presenters, actors and voiceover artists – they’re usually professionals because they’re good at their jobs. A good voiceover artist will deliver an expressive and lively  read of a script, which can really lift a film or animation. Using your staff will be cheaper, but should also contribute something else to the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-to-know-octopus-energy&quot;&gt;Getting to know Octopus Energy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve recently made a number of videos featuring the team at Octopus Energy. It’s a startup challenging the ‘big six’ energy suppliers by offering better customer service and lower prices for new and existing customers – the big six typically charge much more to long-term customers than new ones. So why have we used its team on camera?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly we wanted to create trust. It is a big decision to switch energy supplier, particularly to a startup you may never have heard of before. People tend to trust people they feel they’ve met. That’s why most crowdfunding videos start and end with a piece-to-camera by the founder of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1R8-i9yuRHw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also wanted to show what Octopus Energy stands for. The company’s founder, Greg Jackson, is genuinely passionate about changing the energy market by giving people a better deal and making it more sustainable. This makes him a fantastic front man. Likewise his young team are articulate, intelligent and committed – these qualities all shine through on video and make it feel like you’re getting to know the people behind the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we wanted to use the videos to demonstrate the expertise of the staff at Octopus. Who better to explain how to switch energy providers than the people who will help you switch? We’ve therefore made a series of explainer videos with Octopus’s energy specialists. We’ve also made more ‘thought leadership’ style films with Octopus’s in-house data scientist, David Sykes, about the iniquities of the energy market and what could be done to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cast-carefully&quot;&gt;Cast carefully&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how best to use your team on camera? First, take care with casting.  Don’t always assume your CEO should present everything. They might be the right person, but sometimes they won’t be. Think about who is best to represent your organisation for this particular film, what you want to communicate and and who knows most about the subject at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People you think will be good on camera often are, but it is definitely worth your while giving a few of your team a screen test. That only need involve filming them explaining something to camera. If someone doesn’t want to be filmed, that usually means they won’t be good, as they have already convinced themselves they won’t be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;would-an-interview-be-easier&quot;&gt;Would an interview be easier?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking directly to a camera can be surprisingly difficult – it can feel weird talking to an inanimate object. An alternative is to film your staff being interviewed, which is a much more natural experience. We did that with three members of the City of London Sinfonia for a film recently and edited the interviews with footage of them performing. They were great on camera: articulate and passionate about why the orchestra is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;easy-wins&quot;&gt;Easy wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However you decide to capture your contributors, there are a few key things to remember before pressing record. Try not to tell people to relax, it has a similar effect as telling an angry person not to shout. Also, allow people to speak in their own words. If there’s a script, let them adapt it into their own words – that is what TV news presenters do. And think of ways to help people remember what they’re meant to be saying – we used printed cards in some of the videos we made for Octopus, which was simple but effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Clh7lX1BQgo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Considering casting your team in a marketing video? Here is how to get the best out of your staff in front of the camera.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/08/03/DSC00491.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Show and tell: on location for the Publishers’ Association</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/11/11/publishers-association.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show and tell: on location for the Publishers’ Association" /><published>2015-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/11/11/publishers-association</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/11/11/publishers-association.html">&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of textbooks in schools has been a matter of dispute for some time. Very few children use them in the classroom in the UK compared to countries with more successful education systems, such as Finland and Singapore. And the education minister, Nick Gibb, has even said that teachers have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/education-30129639&quot;&gt;‘ideological hostility’&lt;/a&gt; to using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Publishers Association therefore wanted to make the case for teaching resources via a short video aimed at ministers, policymakers and opinion-formers in the education sector. They asked Happen Digital to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the PA’s team to identify the key messages the video would need to communicate. Some of these were about challenging outdated notions of what teaching resources actually are in the 21st century. They’re not just textbooks and handouts, but sophisticated digital products, including video, audio, games and tools for tracking student attainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed what would be the best format to get these points across. We considered animation, which is popular at the moment for advocacy and explainer videos. But we felt that viewers would want to see teaching resources being used in the classroom, and hear from the children and teachers using them, as well as experts from the publishing industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advocacy videos work best when they feature a number of different voices backing up their main message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we fixed on a mix of location filming, sit-down interviews and simple, elegant motion graphics, which illustrated a few key statistics and comparisons to reinforce the points being made in the audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/127523226?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were helped by having two eloquent and authoritative publishers, Lis Tribe from Hodder Education and Colin Hughes from Collins Learning. They were happy to appear on camera and we asked them to concentrate on a couple of key points each to make the best use of the time we had with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also decided to take them both on location to illustrate how closely the publishing industry works with teachers and schools; and make sure we had some good shots to accompany the points they were making. This led us to a primary school with Colin and the BETT education trade show with Lis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was these visits that really made the video work: we were able to see a class actually using teaching materials and hear how much they valued them. And at the BETT show we saw the range of resources available to schools and the amount of digital innovation in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t script any interviews – we knew what points we wanted the video to make but we wanted our interviewees to feel comfortable expressing themselves in their own words. The result looks and sounds much more natural than if we had arrived with a page for our interviewees to read out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to measure the success of this sort of video, as persuasion is not easy to analyse. But we think the end result works. It’s more than just a few talking heads parroting marketing-speak. Instead we captured real people giving real insight into an industry that touches everyone who’s ever been to school.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The effectiveness of textbooks in schools has been a matter of dispute for some time. Very few children use them in the classroom in the UK compared to countries with more successful education systems, such as Finland and Singapore. And the education minister, Nick Gibb, has even said that teachers have an ‘ideological hostility’ to using them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/07/28/PubAssoc05.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Train your staff to make great videos</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/25/how-to-train-your-staff-to-make-videos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Train your staff to make great videos" /><published>2015-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/25/how-to-train-your-staff-to-make-videos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/25/how-to-train-your-staff-to-make-videos.html">&lt;p&gt;If your content strategy involves publishing regular video, it’s worth thinking about training your staff to produce it. You’ll need to commit some resources to the project but with a modest outlay it’s possible to equip your marketing or communications teams to make regular content in-house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most important is to have a clear idea of what you want them to produce before training starts. Know your objectives and be realistic. If your team are beginners and not about to devote themselves full-time to video production they need to focus on something simple: regular interviews with customers, for example, or pieces-to-camera with your CEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about what your audience will expect in terms of quality and don’t set your team up to fail. They’ll be able to produce professional-looking interviews but not elaborate films. Their work will liven up your blog but probably not look slick at the top of your homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A clear idea of what your team will be producing should inform their training. There’s no better way of learning how to make a video than by actually making a video, delivering it to a deadline and then doing it all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with it’s useful to think of people as video generalists. Everyone should have a good grounding in shooting, sound recording and editing. Then with a few projects under their belts, it might become apparent that people have different skills or preferences that makes a specific role (e.g. editor or producer) a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;training-days&quot;&gt;Training days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you don’t commission training all in one lump. It’s much better to split up a week of training into three one-day sessions and two follow-up clinics. I’ve trained people at the Guardian and Mumsnet and found that little and often is always best. That way the trainees can follow up after they’ve tried things out in production and have specific problems they’re trying to solve. A solid week spent in a meeting room staring at a PowerPoint presentation won’t be nearly as useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training sessions should be practical: everyone should be able to have a go and all the trainees should watch each others’ work. It will help their development a lot if a there’s a culture of sharing knowledge and feedback right from the start of their training. Making videos is a collaborative, physical process and that should inform how your staff learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopping-for-kit&quot;&gt;Shopping for kit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask your trainer’s advice on equipment. If they know what you’re going to be producing they will be able to guide you on what you need. To start with it’s a good idea to establish a relationship with a hire company, and later on it might be worth buying a camera, microphone and lights to give you more flexibility in how you plan your shoots. If you look after your kit you should budget for it to last three years of daily use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-training&quot;&gt;Post-training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your team will only be producing video occasionally they should focus on a simple and repeatable format, such as an interview. Getting the basics right will introduce skills that your staff will use every time they press record. If you want to add some visual pizzazz consider investing in some motion graphics: this will also help to make sure your videos are a natural extension of your brand’s online presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your team grow in confidence and skills they might want to add a presenter and a second camera. Maybe it would be good for your remote workers or users to be able to tune in on a livestream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good foundation in the basics, your production team will be learning more skills as they go. And if you’ve approached your projects one step at a time you’ll be able to expand what you’re doing incrementally without ever biting off more than you can chew.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If your content strategy involves publishing regular video, it’s worth thinking about training your staff to produce it. You’ll need to commit some resources to the project but with a modest outlay it’s possible to equip your marketing or communications teams to make regular content in-house.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/07/28/DSCF1018-820px.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to commission good video: five rules for event filming</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/filming/commissioning/2015/03/17/commissioning-good-video.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to commission good video: five rules for event filming" /><published>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/filming/commissioning/2015/03/17/commissioning-good-video</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/filming/commissioning/2015/03/17/commissioning-good-video.html">&lt;p&gt;Five words to chill the blood of a video producer: ‘Can you film our event?’ It sounds so easy, so straightforward, but it can be a deeply frustrating experience. This is because most events are organised for the benefit of the people attending, not the cameras. This is understandable, but means you should think before pressing record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video team at the Guardian was often asked to ‘capture” an event. ‘It’ll be like TED,’ we were told, but it never was. TED is an online phenomenon because it’s a format that works on the web. Talks are short, rarely lasting more than twenty minutes. People speak without notes or a lectern, and are usually accompanied by strong visuals or video. TED’s reputation also means that speakers raise their game and usually give a great performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Television goes even further. It only films a show in front of an audience when they add to the finished programme. They might contribute something vital, like the questions for Question Time. They might add atmosphere or real laughter. Or they might inspire better comedy performances out of the panel on a shows like Have I Got News For You.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But few of us can afford Paul Merton and Ian Hislop to spice up a corporate event, so what should you bear in mind when considering capturing a speaking panel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-be-clear-about-what-youre-trying-to-achieve-by-filming-it&quot;&gt;1. Be clear about what you’re trying to achieve by filming it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means knowing in advance who you want to reach, what you want to tell them and what you want them to do after watching. You should also identify where your video will be published and how it will find an audience. This will give you a good sense of how long a video people are likely to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to highlight a particular issue discussed by your panel? Or do you want to establish your company as a thought leader in its sector that organises stimulating, well-attended debates? If it is the latter, you should probably keep the video tight, capture a sense of the atmosphere and include voxpops with members of the audience enthusing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-is-it-worth-doing-additional-filming&quot;&gt;2. Is it worth doing additional filming?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve spent weeks or even months setting the agenda, confirming speakers and publicising your event. It’s worth spending a little longer working out if there’s any footage you could capture that isn’t someone at a lectern. Maybe you could record your speakers in a more informal setting before or after they go onstage. Perhaps you want to show the ambience of the venue. Do you want to hear what the audience think? These elements can be added to a package based on presentations, but bear in mind they’ll all add to the length of your video – and often briefer is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-make-sure-your-crew-know-what-is-going-to-happen-and-when&quot;&gt;3. Make sure your crew know what is going to happen and when.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will have to set up their positions beforehand and probably won’t be able to move during the event. This means it’s really important to have a firm idea of how the stage will look, who will be sitting where and the order in which people will be speaking. What is the format of the event? Is there a lectern onstage? Will there be questions from the floor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-brief-your-chair&quot;&gt;4. Brief your chair.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you’re on the same page before the event starts. What’s the format of the event? Will there be prepared speeches or will the chair be expected to mediate a more freeform discussion? Either can work in video but making a decision in conjunction with your chair will mean you’ll have fewer surprises on the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are certain answers you’d like to capture on camera, tell your chair so they can put a specific question to each of the participants in turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-is-it-worth-streaming&quot;&gt;5. Is it worth streaming?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advances in technology mean it’s much cheaper than it used to be to stream your event in video on internet, especially if you’re using a service like YouTube which doesn’t involve a big upfront cost. It’s worth asking yourself why you’re streaming though – and who might be tuning in. Is it a big launch that is oversubscribed for people to attend in person? An all-hands internal briefing? Might people want to participate remotely via social media?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some careful thought and a bit of planning, your next event video can be pithy, classy and a great advertisement for your company.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Five words to chill the blood of a video producer: ‘Can you film our event?’ It sounds so easy, so straightforward, but it can be a deeply frustrating experience. This is because most events are organised for the benefit of the people attending, not the cameras. This is understandable, but means you should think before pressing record.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/07/28/ted_talk.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to commission good video: know your objectives</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/10/commission-good-video-know-your-objectives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to commission good video: know your objectives" /><published>2015-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/10/commission-good-video-know-your-objectives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2015/03/10/commission-good-video-know-your-objectives.html">&lt;p&gt;It was straightforward when I worked in television. We made video because that was just what we did, and the success, or otherwise, of a programme was measured largely by its viewing figures. Things became more complicated when we started to produce video at the Guardian. What stories and subjects would work in video and what formats worked best online were questions we struggled to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I work with companies and other non-media organisations producing video (as well as helping with their content marketing and digital communications) I see similar questions going unanswered until too late. Beautiful videos are being made that are utterly unsuited for the things they’re meant to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is often down to commissioning rather than execution. People don’t explain what they’re trying to achieve because they think they have a clear idea of what format they want. If a production company understands your objectives, what audience you’re trying to reach and where your video will appear and be promoted, you’ll get a much better film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, be clear about why you’re producing a video. This sounds obvious but it is amazing how many people commission video with only the haziest notion of what their objective is. Is it to sell something, persuade people to act in a certain way or present your company in a favourable light?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, decide who your audience is. If you have user personas, they should help you identify what your audience is interested in, where you can reach them online, and how they’re likely to be accessing the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short video aimed at teenagers browsing Instagram via their mobiles should be very different to one targeted at middle-aged managing directors looking at LinkedIn on their desktop computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re trying to persuade people of something, you’ll need to identify what points you want your video to make. Video can be  a much more powerful medium than text but it can only convey a comparatively small number of points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re looking to promote something it is helpful to consider where your video sits on your customers’ journey. Are you trying to make people aware of your product or services? You should be producing either what YouTube calls hero video, something jaw-dropping enough to be shared across social media, or hygiene video, which answers questions people are asking Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to share things that are funny or moving, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZUG9qYTJMsI&quot;&gt;Dollar Shave Club&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RBQ-IoHfimQ&quot;&gt;Most Shocking Second a Day&lt;/a&gt; are good examples of hero videos. And as people turn to YouTube to see how to do almost everything, hygiene videos can cover anything from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8dCZm5aLj9A&quot;&gt;how to boil an egg&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QeQFEt-JuJ8&quot;&gt;how to build your own Death Star in Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further along your customer journey people might simply want to watch a video explaining what your product or service does or see satisfied customers explaining why they’d recommend it. If buying the product online can be tricky - as it can be on some financial services websites - you might even want a video to explain that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the most brilliant video will struggle to find an audience without a distribution strategy. So you need to think about how you’re going to persuade people to watch it and whether you’re going to commit ad spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarity about objectives should help you commission a video that is right for you. It should also help you define what metrics to monitor and ultimately how to determine whether you’re getting a return on your investment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It was straightforward when I worked in television. We made video because that was just what we did, and the success, or otherwise, of a programme was measured largely by its viewing figures. Things became more complicated when we started to produce video at the Guardian. What stories and subjects would work in video and what formats worked best online were questions we struggled to answer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/07/11/IMG_2438.JPG" /></entry></feed>