<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-03T15:30:38+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/</id><title type="html">Happen Digital</title><subtitle>Content to make complicated things clear
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Show and tell: inspiring viewers through emotion</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/11/20/show-and-tell-inspiring-viewers-through-emotion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show and tell: inspiring viewers through emotion" /><published>2018-11-20T16:39:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-20T16:39:04+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/11/20/show-and-tell-inspiring-viewers-through-emotion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/11/20/show-and-tell-inspiring-viewers-through-emotion.html">&lt;p&gt;We used a very simple device in a short film we made for Teach First recently. We interviewed three teachers at a school in a deprived area in south London and asked them what inspired them about their pupils. We then surprised them with videos of their pupils explaining how their teachers have in turn inspired them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prompted very genuine, emotional reactions from all the participants, giving the film an emotional core that can’t help but inspire the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vg1vJLDTNrs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film was for Teach First’s annual fundraising dinner, and has subsequently been used on its social media channels. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teachfirst.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Teach First is a charity that encourages highflying graduates to go into teaching&lt;/a&gt;, learning on the job, in some of the country’s most deprived schools. They are one of our favourite clients, and an organisation we’re proud to work for – &lt;a href=&quot;https://happendigital.co.uk/case/teachfirst.html&quot;&gt;you can see more of the films we’ve made them here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film was made over two days, and involved some swift editing overnight. The first day was spent with the students, gathering b-roll and interviewing them speaking straight into the camera lens. We don’t often shoot like this but here we wanted the teachers and viewer to feel the students were talking directly to them. The second day was spent with the teachers, interviewing them in a traditional way but also using a laptop to show them the student interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results were exactly what we wanted: an engaging film that made its point with emotion. We were able to demonstrate to the people helping to fund Teach First how important the work they’re enabling is, and the positive effect it’s having on communities facing a lot of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We used a very simple device in a short film we made for Teach First recently. We interviewed three teachers at a school in a deprived area in south London and asked them what inspired them about their pupils. We then surprised them with videos of their pupils explaining how their teachers have in turn inspired them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/11/28/Teach%20First%20Brixton%20big%20picture.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacking it: how to use your hack day to market your company</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/31/hacking-it-how-to-use-your-hack-day-to-market-your-company.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacking it: how to use your hack day to market your company " /><published>2018-10-31T14:27:15+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T14:27:15+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/31/hacking-it-how-to-use-your-hack-day-to-market-your-company</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/31/hacking-it-how-to-use-your-hack-day-to-market-your-company.html">&lt;p&gt;Hack days are a great way to unleash your team’s creativity, bring people together and generate new products and services. They are usually one or two-day events where developers, designers and other come together to build new things. They are often competitive, with prizes for the best ideas. The more diverse the hack teams, the more interesting the hacks. That is why people often invite teams from other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transparency is one of the most effective ways to market a business, particularly a B2B one. If you’re innovative, collaborative, and open to new ideas, let people know about it. You’ll win more business, and recruit better people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happen worked with Octopus Energy to promote &lt;a href=&quot;https://octopus.energy/hackday/&quot;&gt;its hack day&lt;/a&gt;. Other innovative, tech-driven companies in the energy sector were invited to see what they could do with the Agile Octopus tariff. This gives people access to half-hourly energy prices, tied to wholesale rates and updated throughout the day. So if people shift their energy consumption to times when demand is lower they pay less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/273657634&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how to make the most out of your hack day as part of your marketing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about what and how you want to communicate before, during and after the hack day. If it is an internal event or invite only, your communication needs to be clear and comprehensive. If you’re trying to reach new people, you probably also want a dedicated landing page or website, and an online event service to allow people to sign up. You’ll also want to promote your hack day on Twitter and Facebook and via relevant Google and LinkedIn groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also invite journalists and bloggers to your hack day. Bear in mind that they are much more likely to come if you ask them to judge the projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plan the day carefully. It shouldn’t just run smoothly, it should also have a sense of drama and fun. Have an MC welcome everyone and update people about the time remaining throughout the day. Think about the presentations – don’t let things drag on too long – and have different categories (with different prizes!). This is particularly important if you’re filming the day. A hack day is a format, with a clear story, like the Great British Bake Off. So think about what key moments you need to capture, and who your key characters are. Make sure your MC and judges are good on camera, and that you show the true diversity of your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day itself, you will obviously need a robust network and excellent WiFi. You should also have a hashtag and to encourage participants to Tweet, post, etc about the event. You should do the same, ideally sharing photos and short videos as well as text. Be aware that not everyone likes being photographed and filmed – check that people are happy for you to snap them first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re filming, be clear about the type of film you want. A single camera operator cannot film every second of every presentation if they’re also capturing audience reaction. Octopus wanted a film giving a sense of the day. We filmed its key moments and captured a good mix of footage: interviews and fly-on-the-wall b-roll, including moments with natural sound, which help bring a film alive for the viewer. We used music to add drama and timelapse video to show the passage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve inviting external teams to your hack day, think about how you can help them promote themselves, and you in the process. During the Octopus hack day, &lt;a href=&quot;https://octopus.energy/blog/hacking-the-future-of-energy/&quot;&gt;we filmed and edited a number of short films about individual teams&lt;/a&gt; during the day itself. Octopus was therefore able to give them the videos to share on their social media channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the event, let journalists and bloggers know about the winners. Write about it on your blog and share your film on social media. But also think longer-term. If any of the hacks turn into something bigger, tell people about it, including members of the other teams. Make sure you explain how your new product or service came about, and how your hack day was so crucial to its success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on content marketing for technology companies, download our white paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/05/a-practical-guide-to-content-marketing-for-b2b-technology-companies.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hack days are a great way to unleash your team’s creativity, bring people together and generate new products and services. They are usually one or two-day events where developers, designers and other come together to build new things. They are often competitive, with prizes for the best ideas. The more diverse the hack teams, the more interesting the hacks. That is why people often invite teams from other companies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/10/31/Hack-day-main-image.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Show and tell: creating a global road safety campaign with attitude</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/08/show-and-tell-creating-a-global-road-safety-campaign-with-attitude.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show and tell: creating a global road safety campaign with attitude" /><published>2018-10-08T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/08/show-and-tell-creating-a-global-road-safety-campaign-with-attitude</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/10/08/show-and-tell-creating-a-global-road-safety-campaign-with-attitude.html">&lt;p&gt;Coming up with new ideas is easy. Ones that work in the real world, though, are harder to come by. Briefs are rarely blank sheets of paper: clients want new creative approaches – to their marketing, communications, campaigns – but ones that work with their existing commitments. There are always constraints. True creativity makes a virtue out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiafoundation.org/&quot;&gt;FIA Foundation&lt;/a&gt; asked Happen to help with a new initiative highlighting the dangers children face walking to school. It wanted a fresh approach, but one that worked with its plans and to a tight timetable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIA Foundation is a global charity campaigning for safe, clean, fair and green mobility for all. Road accidents are the bigger killer of children over 10 around the world. Children in the poorest countries are most at risk: the developing world is urbanising rapidly, with little investment in road safety measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/372598039&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FIA Foundation wanted to avoid portraying children just as victims. It wanted to present walking to school as a positive thing: a way children develop a sense of independence, an important part of growing up. It wanted the children in its campaign to have a sense of agency and strong voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what were the constraints?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIA Foundation had a relationship with the Jamaican two-times Olympic 100-metres champion Shelly-Ann Fraser-Pryce, and with the Jamaican government, which it was working with to improve road safety. It therefore wanted to film in Jamaica and feature Shelly-Ann in the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also had a tight timetable: Shelly-Ann was only free to film in early March, there was only budget for three shooting days, and the campaign had to be ready to launch to accompany a report in late May. It wanted to involve children, but did not have time for preproduction in Jamaica. Usually if you feature children in a campaign, you spend time casting them, making sure you find children who will be comfortable and confident on camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/270610612&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the FIA Foundation wanted a video format that could be replicated in other countries, by freelance film crews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind we worked with the FIA Foundation team to develop a creative concept for the campaign and formats for two short films, which could be shot quickly. We came up with the idea of “My Street” – an assertion that children have ownership of the streets where they walk, and demand that motorists respect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shelly-Ann film would feature her returning to her old school, talking about her journey there and back each day and what it meant to her. We were only going to have a morning with her, so from London we produced a shooting structure, shot listing and script that told her story. The script was based on detailed research into her life and a brief phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allowed us to work quickly on location, capturing a piece-to-camera and script read from her, as well as an interview and actuality of her conversations with the students. In the end, we had less than two-hours with her, so our approach to preproduction paid off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIA Foundation wanted to feature children from schools in some of the poorest areas in Jamaica, in downtown Kingston and in the countryside, outside the capital. We developed a simple format and script that would allow us to cut between children delivering different lines. This meant we were not dependent on slick, confident on-camera performances – hard enough to get with adults – and that we could add pace in the edit through fast cuts and onscreen graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/10/09/2018-03-06 13.40.25 copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;We subsequently produced editorial and technical guidelines to enable an international version of the format to be made – shot by different crews – featuring children from the US, Tanzania and London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIA Foundation used the “My Street” concept and the two films as the core of its campaign with its nineteen global partners in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childhealthinitiative.org/&quot;&gt;Child Health Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which includes the UN Environment Programme, Save the Children and UNICEF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shelly-Ann film reached over 1.25 million people, with UNICEF UK and UNICEF Jamaica the most successful at sharing the video via their Facebook and Twitter accounts. There were over 50,000 views of the video on the Child Health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initiative Twitter account alone, and over 100,000 impressions, with a 2% engagement rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the Child Health Initiative partners’ local affiliates created their own campaign material using the “This is my Street” slogan in their own languages. The Shelly-Ann film was also translated into Spanish and used by UNICEF in Latin America and the Caribbean for its Streets for Life launch in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The films have had a long tail and are still being used, with the childrens’ films being used to promote the International Walk to School Month this October.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Coming up with new ideas is easy. Ones that work in the real world, though, are harder to come by. Briefs are rarely blank sheets of paper: clients want new creative approaches – to their marketing, communications, campaigns – but ones that work with their existing commitments. There are always constraints. True creativity makes a virtue out of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/10/09/2018-03-06%2019.53.33%20copy.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Show and tell: bringing artificial intelligence to life</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/09/18/show-and-tell-bringing-artificial-intelligence-to-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show and tell: bringing artificial intelligence to life" /><published>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/09/18/show-and-tell-bringing-artificial-intelligence-to-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/09/18/show-and-tell-bringing-artificial-intelligence-to-life.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cogisen.com/&quot;&gt;Cogisen&lt;/a&gt; is a startup using artificial intelligence and machine learning to extract context and intent from content. The company approached Happen about making a short film for its website and presentations to introduce its business to new clients and potential hires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/282641326&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cogisen’s founder, Christiaan Rijnders, wanted to focus on the team they’re building and not just himself, to emphasise the collaborative nature of the work they’re doing. He wanted the film to have a documentary look and feel. And he wanted it to explain their technology without giving too much away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We faced a common challenge to making a film about a lot of tech companies: what to actually show beyond pictures of software engineers typing on a computer. There’s only so much b-roll of fingers on keys a viewer can take. Cogisen is committed to questioning the state of the art, being adventurous in its thinking and engaging with problems from first principles, so the film had to somehow illustrate that spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start with we highlighted Rome – where Cogisen is based – an extraordinary city where ancient monuments stand side by side with modern architecture (and traffic), and which is a perfect illustration both of the power of human ingenuity and Cogisen’s commitment to building something that would stand the test of time. We also felt working there would be a significant draw for potential hires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought it important to film the Cogisen team socialising together, to illustrate the collaborative nature of their work and commitment to challenging and learning from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/09/18/195A1773.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we asked about the team’s interests and passions outside of work. It turned out that Cogisen’s engineering and design lead, Damon Millar, is a passionate cyclist involved in a side project designing a new type of triathlon bike. Talking to him it became obvious that the idea of ‘peak aero’ in cycle design had parallels with the problem of diminishing returns in traditional machine learning that Cogisen was hoping to help solve. And cycling through the Italian countryside would give us some dynamic, eye-catching footage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company also has a lab where they use a specialised interface to log brain activity in test subjects. We secured a willing volunteer and shot Cogisen’s resident expert in neuroscience setting up the equipment and taking some readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This variety of setups makes the finished film more watchable and allowed us to choose when to cut back to the interviewees. You can never have enough b-roll! It gives a taste of what the company’s technology is capable of, makes the most of the Cogisen team and positions them as innovators in an exciting field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”Quite a challenge, to avoid the standard cliché’s when introducing an engineering company that operates in several industry verticals using fast-developing technology (the details of which are only of interest to a few experts!). But that is why we need professionals like Happen. We are more than happy with the result. I’m impressed how they captured the working culture and philosophy of Cogisen.“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christiaan Rijnders, CEO &amp;amp; Founder, Cogisen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on content marketing for technology companies, download our white paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/05/a-practical-guide-to-content-marketing-for-b2b-technology-companies.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cogisen is a startup using artificial intelligence and machine learning to extract context and intent from content. The company approached Happen about making a short film for its website and presentations to introduce its business to new clients and potential hires. Cogisen’s founder, Christiaan Rijnders, wanted to focus on the team they’re building and not just himself, to emphasise the collaborative nature of the work they’re doing. He wanted the film to have a documentary look and feel. And he wanted it to explain their technology without giving too much away.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/09/18/195A1920.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">show and tell: The power of Something Happening</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/02/06/the-power-of-something-happening.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="show and tell: The power of Something Happening" /><published>2018-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/02/06/the-power-of-something-happening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/02/06/the-power-of-something-happening.html">&lt;p&gt;When we’re approached by anyone who wants to make a film, a question we always ask is: what is there to show?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds basic but film is a visual medium and too often you don’t see anything happening in online videos: lots of chat but very little in the way of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/06/DSCF7416.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we jumped at the chance to make a short film about photographer Niall McDiarmid’s street portrait project, Town to Town. Niall (seen on the left above with Martin Parr at the exhibition’s opening) has spent the last seven years travelling all over the country meeting people, taking their picture and building up a photographic portrait of contemporary Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A selection of his work is now on show at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.martinparrfoundation.org/exhibitions/town-to-town/&quot;&gt;Martin Parr Foundation in Bristol&lt;/a&gt; and we’re thrilled that our film is part of the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/251490728&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth a lot of Niall’s practice is based on patience: waiting for the right person to come along and timing his approach to maximise the chances of their agreeing to a photo. As a filmmaker the challenge was to stay alert for those moments and get the maximum amount of coverage – shots that would cut together – from an interaction that might only last a couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might mean in some cases that the footage is a bit wobbly and takes a while to find focus – but what makes it watchable nevertheless is the fact that you’re watching something happen. You’re not just hearing a talking head describe a photographic practice, you’re seeing it play out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/02/06/DSCF7409.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you watch the film it’s also clear how important audio is to the finished piece. Listening to Niall’s approach you can understand why people agree to have their photo taken: he’s charming, persistent and makes his subjects feel like they’re worthy of the attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, just like the exhibition itself: if you’re in the Bristol area &lt;a href=&quot;http://paintworksbristol.co.uk/home/&quot;&gt;do pop into the Paintworks&lt;/a&gt; and take a look.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When we’re approached by anyone who wants to make a film, a question we always ask is: what is there to show?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/02/06/DSCF7425-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to commission good video: producing an effective case study</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/25/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-an-effective-case-study.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to commission good video: producing an effective case study" /><published>2018-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/25/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-an-effective-case-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/25/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-an-effective-case-study.html">&lt;p&gt;Case study films are an effective way to show potential customers the benefits of your products or services. They can play a vital role in the customer journey: providing the reassurance people need ahead of a purchase. They work particularly well for new products and services or ones involving substantial expenditure or that are perceived as risky. People trust people without a vested interest to recommend things, as the popularity of TripAdvisor and Trustpilot proves. So a video featuring one or more of your clients explaining how you have helped their business is very persuasive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/181762872&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happen has made case study films for a number of organisations, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, the communications app company; so here is what you need to bear in mind if you are commissioning one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understand your customers, products and services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start, be clear about who you are trying to reach and how your product or service would help them. You should have an audience in mind before commissioning any piece of content, but it is particularly important when commissioning a case study, as its purpose is to illustrate how you can solve some of their business’s problems. This of course requires you to understand how your products or services actually help your customers. That should be your focus. Don’t only think about the company, think roles too: if you’re targeting financial directors focus on cost efficiency and value. This sounds obvious but too much marketing concentrates on a product or service’s features rather than its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Find a good agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good agency should be curious about your product or services. It needs to understand how you help your customers, if it is going to capture that in video. It should therefore listen but also offer advice; don’t hire an agency that says yes to everything without questioning whether they are best for the film. Equally do not hire one that confuses things. You should expect to see examples of its work and a breakdown of its quoted costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our background in journalism, Happen likes to spend time understanding a new client at the start of a project. We like to meet people across the organisation, either one-to-one or in a workshop, to get a clear picture of its culture and strategy and how its goods and services helps its customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cast carefully&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of your film will depend on how good the people are in it. If they are articulate, lively and passionate they will be persuasive. If they represent a company that your target audience admires, trusts and can relate to, their words will carry more weight. And if they work somewhere visually interesting, your film will be more watchable. It therefore pays to think carefully about who you cast in your case study. If people are proving reluctant to appear, explain that the film will promote their business as well as yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/181763392&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider casting more than one person from a company. A range of people will make your film more lively. It can also illustrate how your goods or services help people working across a business. Our case study about how Slack helped Ocado Technology (embedded above) was only 90 seconds long but it still featured three interviewees: its chief operating officer, a department head and a team leader. You also need to decide whether someone from your company should appear in the film. Obviously this makes more sense if you are providing a professional service rather than a product. If you are, it can work to have one of your team outlining how you approached your client’s needs alongside its team explaining how great that has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be specific&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to include specific examples of how your product or service has helped your customer in your film. Support assertions with examples. In a case study about M&amp;amp;S Digital we made for Slack, one of the interviewees describes how she used its app to sort out a software problem she saw when she was out of the office visiting a call centre. She was able to report it back to her team, take and send a photo, and get it fixed while she was there. Her anecdote showed exactly how Slack made M&amp;amp;S Digital more agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/152813483&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your film can also rebut any concerns that your would-be customers may have. We also made a case study for Consultant Connect, which enables GPs to speak directly to hospital consultants during consultations, thereby reducing the number of referrals. One worry it encounters is a fear among consultants that they will end up spending too much time on the phone. The film therefore featured a consultant explaining how little time he spends on the phone talking to GPS, and how it in fact saves him time in the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being specific will also help your film tell a story. Most people are much more receptive to information if it is conveyed via a story. Stories also communicate positive change, which is something most companies want to argue that their products and services bring about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Think pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good pictures will make your film watchable, so think about what you can film as well as who you can interview. Try to not just shoot inside offices. You can be imaginative if you have no choice, using movement and interesting angles, but it is better if you can also film elsewhere. And give yourself time to film things, do not spend all your time on interviews. We made a 90-second case study for the charity Teach First and it included footage from four different locations: the exterior of an Oxford college, its library and dining hall, and an inner London school classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/25/Case-study-TeachFirst-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your options are limited ask your client if they have any footage you can use. You’ll surprised how many companies do, and your film about an oil company’s data team will be a lot more interesting with footage of an oil rig. In our Slack case study about Ocado we used footage of its amazing automated warehouse. This allowed us to tell the story about how Slack helped connect the testing team in a new warehouse with the developers in the main office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, your film should start with amazing, attention-grabbing footage and include sequences of shots illustrating a story. A good range of footage will also give you choices in the edit and the ability to cut up the interviews so they are as tight and to-the-point as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get the best out of your interviewees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your interviews as relaxed as possible. Put people at their ease by explaining what you are trying to achieve and that your aim is not to grill them like a politician. You should be persuading them to repeat the things they told you during preproduction, not trying to get them to say things you think. Ask open questions, nod and smile during their answers. And don’t be afraid about asking them how they feel. Emotion can make a film much more effective at getting&lt;br /&gt;
a message across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keep it short&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are busy. More of them will watch a short film than a long one.  Aim for a length of 90 seconds to two-minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Find out more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more about content marketing download our practical guide. It is written for B2B technology companies but would be helpful for any marketer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Case study films are an effective way to show potential customers the benefits of your products or services. They can play a vital role in the customer journey: providing the reassurance people need ahead of a purchase. They work particularly well for new products and services or ones involving substantial expenditure or that are perceived as risky. People trust people without a vested interest to recommend things, as the popularity of TripAdvisor and Trustpilot proves. So a video featuring one or more of your clients explaining how you have helped their business is very persuasive.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/01/25/Case-study-Slack-01.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Show and tell: filming a feast with Sabrina Ghayour</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/17/show-and-tell-filming-a-feast-with-sabrina-ghayour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show and tell: filming a feast with Sabrina Ghayour" /><published>2018-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/17/show-and-tell-filming-a-feast-with-sabrina-ghayour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/17/show-and-tell-filming-a-feast-with-sabrina-ghayour.html">&lt;p&gt;Instructional videos are a big deal – arguably one of the most useful ways in which video on the web has evolved. Need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxKA9be_3Gk&quot;&gt;tie a bow tie&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ID26I5ZeWh8&quot;&gt;Rewire a plug&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qGGP2jmR-fc&quot;&gt;Cook Yorkshire puddings&lt;/a&gt;? Chances are you can find a video to show you what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality control however is non-existent, and although you might find a polished video that’s fun to watch and features an articulate presenter, you’re just as likely to end up watching a blurry video shot on someone’s phone that jumps about and features heavy breathing and unclear narration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yodomo.co&quot;&gt;Yodomo&lt;/a&gt; is a startup that wants to change all that, working with creators and artists to develop a range of how-to video series that are beautiful as well as practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/247118429&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yodomo approached Happen when they had the opportunity of filming a series of videos with the brilliant cook and food writer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sabrinaghayour.com&quot;&gt;Sabrina Ghayour&lt;/a&gt;. The brief was to record some friendly advice on entertaining with food as well as demonstrate some recipes from Sabrina’s new book Feasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over two days we shot material for a course of ten videos, culminating in the creation of three delicious recipes: Beer roasted pork, Burrata with pomegranate seeds and Fig and Honey Millefeuille.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On set with us were Yodomo founder Sophie Rochester (seen below with the finished feast), stylist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kathrinmccreaphotography.co.uk&quot;&gt;Kathrin McCrea&lt;/a&gt; and home economist &lt;a href=&quot;https://udoreicheltschaurer.com&quot;&gt;Udo Reicheltschaurer&lt;/a&gt; as well as the star of the show, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/sabrinaghayour/?hl=en&quot; title=&quot;Sabrina's Instagram&quot;&gt;Sabrina herself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/01/17/Sabrina-and-Sophie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sabrina Ghayour and Sophie Rochester&quot; title=&quot;Sabrina Ghayour, Yodomo's Sophie Rochester and the finished feast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days was an ambitious schedule and so we shot all the recipes on two cameras to give us options in the edit – ideally it would have been nice to have another angle as well. You can never have too much coverage when you’re trying to capture a process like following a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all so used to watching cookery programmes on TV where the food is the real star of the show – and the challenge on this job was trying to make the most of Sabrina’s delicious recipes on a relatively modest budget. With careful lighting and a good relationship with both the client and the talent, we were able to help Yodomo create a Feast of a video series, and one that we’re all very proud of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Instructional videos are a big deal – arguably one of the most useful ways in which video on the web has evolved. Need to tie a bow tie? Rewire a plug? Cook Yorkshire puddings? Chances are you can find a video to show you what to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2018/01/17/DSC00781.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to commission good video: producing effective animation</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/10/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-effective-animation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to commission good video: producing effective animation" /><published>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/10/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-effective-animation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2018/01/10/how-to-commission-good-video-producing-effective-animation.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to explain your goods and services to potential customers is with an explainer animation. It is a more involved process than making a live action video, so here are a few things to bear in mind if you’re commissioning an animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animation is a great way to bring to life something that isn’t particularly visual – for example, a complicated process or dry facts and figures. It can also add charm and humour to a subject. This means people are more likely to devote a few minutes to watching your video. They’re also more likely to share it via social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re clear about your objectives, find a good agency to work with. It should be committed to understanding what you’re trying to achieve and making the process as straightforward and simple for you as possible. If they confuse you, go elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animation is a step-by-step process, so there are a number of sign off points along the way. You should be delighted by the end result but not surprised by it – because you should have been involved in each stage of production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth bearing in mind that going back and making changes after a stage has been signed off can add significantly to the cost and time it takes to complete an animation. To avoid delays and cost overruns make sure at every stage that each round of feedback is consolidated from everyone whose opinion matters before sending it on to your agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve clarified your objective and key messages, you should agree with your agency the look and feel you want. You might want to share some examples of animations that you’ve seen and enjoyed. Your agency should then present you with some different styles of illustration to choose from. Once that’s decided the agency should draft a script: this will include voiceover (or the dialogue if it’s interview-based) and a description of what’s happening onscreen. You should be happy with this before proceeding. Don’t be tempted to try and explain absolutely everything in your script. Of course the script must be accurate, but it also needs to flow and be lively. A good way to approach scripting is to see how much you can remove and still have it make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preproduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with the script an illustrator will then take it and produce a storyboard of images that will make up the final animation. This can be as complicated or as simple as you want. Something as lifelike as Frozen would cost a lot of money and would probably be overkill if you’re not going to put substantial promotional spend behind it. Simple can be just as effective. Make sure you’re happy with the storyboard before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also cast your animation: someone to record your script as voiceover. Once you’ve decided what voices you prefer, you should be able to listen into the recording if you wish. You could also ask for an animatic, which is a basic version of the storyboard with simple animations, timed with the audio. This will add to the overall cost, but will also give you a better sense of what the final result will look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/141031500&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the storyboard and the soundtrack are agreed, the animation begins. Production time depends on length, format and style, but you should be able to see a full-length version of the visuals before the audio is added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Postproduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve seen the rough cut of the animation it’s time to add final polish: the voiceover will be mixed with sound effects and any music you’ve chosen. It can be surprising how much the addition of the sound mix can lift a project: often the sound can add clarity and focus to the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step is to render all the pictures and audio into one master file: this will vary depending on exactly how you want to use it but might typically be an HD-sized MP4 file ready to be uploaded to Vimeo, Youtube or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Find out more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more about content marketing download our practical guide. It is written for B2B technology companies but would be helpful for any marketer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One of the best ways to explain your goods and services to potential customers is with an explainer animation. It is a more involved process than making a live action video, so here are a few things to bear in mind if you’re commissioning an animation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/07/17/Case-study-ZPG-07.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kit to kickstart your in-house video production</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/17/the-100-video-kit-kickstart-your-in-house-video.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kit to kickstart your in-house video production" /><published>2017-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/17/the-100-video-kit-kickstart-your-in-house-video</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/17/the-100-video-kit-kickstart-your-in-house-video.html">&lt;p&gt;When we provide video training for clients we’re often asked for advice about what equipment to invest in. Our starting point is always to find out what sort of videos are required – often short interview bites or film video loops for social media – and what the  budgetary constraints are – often as little as possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget: What budget?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what to do if you want to start small? Pretty much every smartphone will record decent video, and with a few add-ons you can improve your production values significantly. The first and most important thing to think about is audio. If you’ve got clear audio your audience will forgive you for not having enormously sophisticated visuals – but if your sound is no good even the prettiest of pictures will fall flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do simple interviews you should get a clip mic. Also known as lavaliers, you’ll have seen these microphones on TV presenters. You clip them to an appropriate piece of clothing and because they’re so close to the source of the sound they cut down background noise when compared to your smartphone’s  built-in microphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smartphone clip mics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/14/Screen Shot 2017-12-14 at 13.37.42.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Rode Smartlav+ microphone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your smartphone has a 3.5mm audio jack you should get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rode.com/microphones/smartlav-plus&quot;&gt;Rode SmartLav+ &lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gak.co.uk/en/rode-sc1-trrs-extension-cable/112308?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIxJfl4NWJ2AIVRrvtCh2BlwV9EAQYAiABEgLKc_D_BwE&quot;&gt;an extension cable&lt;/a&gt; to allow you to step away from your subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple have removed the audio jacks from their most recent iPhones. If you have one of these models (an iPhone 7 or later) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gear4music.com/PA-DJ-and-Lighting/Sennheiser-ClipMic-Digital-iOS-Device-Microphone/1A6H?origin=product-ads&amp;amp;campaign=PLA+Shop+-+GENERIC&amp;amp;adgroup=GENERIC&amp;amp;medium=vertical_search&amp;amp;network=google&amp;amp;merchant_id=1279443&amp;amp;product_id=59849d1&amp;amp;product_country=GB&amp;amp;product_partition_id=136756261519&amp;amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMI2IS0ws-J2AIVSZPtCh2sNgmHEAQYASABEgINnPD_BwE&quot;&gt;you’ll need a mic like this one that will connect to Apple’s proprietary Lightning socket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steady your shot with a tripod&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next item on your list should be a tripod. It might seem like overkill to stabilise a smartphone, but a steady shot will instantly make your videos easier to watch. Inducing motion sickness in your viewers shouldn’t be a KPI for your video strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in it for the long haul you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manfrotto.co.uk/290-light-aluminium-tripod-with-befree-live-fluid-video-head&quot;&gt;get something like this from Manfrotto&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an entry-level video tripod but you’ll be able to use it for years. Otherwise &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;amp;field-keywords=tripod&quot;&gt;Amazon have a range of options that start from around £15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also need a way of attaching your phone to the tripod. Try something like the Glif, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Glif-tripod-quick-release-smartphones/dp/B071WKTMPQ&quot;&gt;an extremely simple mounting system compatible with a wide range of devices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s enough retail therapy for now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now you should stop spending money and go and shoot something – have a play with the tripod and use it to get a variety of shots, and get into the habit of using the mic for your interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going further&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming your first attempts at video have gone well, you might want to go further: more elaborate filming, better-looking interviews, more regular content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/14/DC-GH5KBODY_ALT04.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Panasonic GH5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good step up would be a camera like Panasonic’s GH5. It’s still reasonably compact but shoots good quality video in resolutions up to 4K. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wexphotovideo.com/panasonic-lumix-dmc-gh5-digital-camera-with-12-60mm-f28-40-leica-lens-1616675/&quot;&gt;A package that includes a lens will cost around £2,000&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll also need a couple of SD memory cards, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wexphotovideo.com/panasonic-dmw-blf19-battery-pack-1532814/&quot;&gt;an extra battery&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/External-Hard-Drives-4TB/s?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;rh=n%3A430544031%2Cp_n_size_browse-bin%3A10625611031&quot;&gt;hard drive to back your footage up onto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/12/14/Screen Shot 2017-12-14 at 13.33.15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sennheiser G3 radio mic set&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get some more mileage from the tripod you were using with your smartphone, but the microphones won’t transfer across, sadly. We’d recommend getting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cvp.com/product/sennheiser_ew-112-p-g3&quot;&gt;wireless set like the Sennheiser G3&lt;/a&gt;. This has a transmitter you clip onto your interviewee and a receiver that will plug straight into the GH5 and give you great interview audio. You should also buy a set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Sony-MDRZX110B-AE-MDR-ZX110-Headphones-Black/dp/B00NBR70DO/ref=sr_1_cc_4?s=aps&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1513252655&amp;amp;sr=1-4-catcorr&amp;amp;keywords=headphones&quot;&gt;headphones&lt;/a&gt; so you can listen to the sound while you’re recording it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next steps: Lighting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To raise your production values again you should get some lighting to avoid the horror of shooting interviews in overhead fluorescent lighting. Just look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jonroemer.com/2017/12/why-light-video-interview-lighting-setup/&quot;&gt;photographer and DoP Jon Roemer’s post here&lt;/a&gt; for a striking before and after shot that shows why it’s a good idea to light interviews!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CfVeGjdOVpU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; gesture=&quot;media&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A standard interview lighting setup has three lights: a main (key) light, a secondary (fill) light and a backlight to help separate your subject from the background. Start off with one light, experiment with it and build your kit as your confidence grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fvlight.eu&quot;&gt;F&amp;amp;V make well-regarded, reasonably priced kit&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cvp.com/product/fv_r300s_se_bicolour_led_ring_light&quot;&gt;R300 is a ring-shaped fixture&lt;/a&gt; that will produce a nice catchlight in your subjects’ eyes. Remember to also buy a stand and a power supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next steps: Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be shooting in your office you should also think about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manfrotto.co.uk/lastolite/background-and-background-support/paper-rolls&quot;&gt;getting a paper backdrop&lt;/a&gt;. Grey looks classy, and brighter colours, like the yellow we used below, will make your videos pop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0797.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy supports for the whole roll, or you could just cut it to size and tape it to a wall. You’ll need to supply your own wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to roll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now find a suitable spot – ideally away from loud air conditioning vents and the coffee machine. Tape your backdrop to the wall, set up your light and find a willing victim – er, interviewee – with something to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you find you need help with any aspect of your content marketing, from training to video production, do get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When we provide video training for clients we’re often asked for advice about what equipment to invest in. Our starting point is always to find out what sort of videos are required – often short interview bites or film video loops for social media – and what the  budgetary constraints are – often as little as possible!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/12/17/DSC00549.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A practical guide to content marketing for B2B technology companies</title><link href="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/05/a-practical-guide-to-content-marketing-for-b2b-technology-companies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A practical guide to content marketing for B2B technology companies" /><published>2017-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/05/a-practical-guide-to-content-marketing-for-b2b-technology-companies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happendigital.co.uk/2017/12/05/a-practical-guide-to-content-marketing-for-b2b-technology-companies.html">&lt;p&gt;Content marketing is as important for B2B companies as B2C ones, if not more so. B2B buyers are much more rigorous in their decision-making than the typical consumer. They want to be certain that what they’re buying will do the job and give them maximum return on their investment. This is particularly true for the technology sector where goods and services are by their nature complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, we’re often surprised by how B2B technology companies struggle with content marketing. Content is produced without a clear understanding of where it fits in the bigger picture. It is also often uninspired, uninteresting and unlikely to persuade anyone of anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set you on the right path, we’ve created this practical guide to help you maximize the return from your firm’s investment in content. It is based on our experience helping big names like Zoopla, Slack and Auto Trader and as journalists – we worked at the BBC, Channel 4 and the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find most companies prefer to produce written content in-house and video out-of-house, so it focuses on how to develop and implement a content strategy and commission key video formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you find the guide helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundations for an effective content strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify your objectives • Understand your target audience • Find the sweet spot • Measure, review, revise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning from the newsroom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editorial mandate • Know the top line • Process and planning • Commission in and out-of-house&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons from Zoopla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explanation backed up with facts is at the heart of Zoopla’s B2B marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to produce effective animation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go from development to post-production to explain your goods and services with charm and humour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Slack does well&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying with customers after purchase, marketing as a part of customer experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to commission a case study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cast carefully • Be specific • Think pictures • Get the most out of interviews&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing your expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about discovery • Identify your expertise • Be consistent and agile • Format and reformat&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Content marketing is as important for B2B companies as B2C ones, if not more so. B2B buyers are much more rigorous in their decision-making than the typical consumer. They want to be certain that what they’re buying will do the job and give them maximum return on their investment. This is particularly true for the technology sector where goods and services are by their nature complex.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://happendigital.co.uk/uploads/2017/12/05/HAPPEN%20zoopla.jpg" /></entry></feed>